lessannoyingcrm.com 2019-01-30

# Privacy and Security Policies

_Note: If you're looking for a plain-English explanation of what we do to keep your data private and secure, you should check out oursecurity center_

At Less Annoying CRM, we are denizens of the web, and we attempt to run our business the way we wish all web-based services would. As such, we respect your personal information and privacy and do everything, within reason, to prevent personal information from being disseminated without your consent. 

**Collected Information**

At times we will collect personally identifiable or private information from you so that you can make use of our service. We never knowingly collect any personal information about people under the age of 13. This collected information includes the following: 

  * Upon registration, we will collect your name, email, and a password. Your password is stored and encoded in a fashion so as to be inaccessible even to Less Annoying CRM employees. All other information will be used only to allow you to log into the system and to enable us to contact you to inform you of product changes, upcoming releases, CRM notifications/reminders, changes to this Privacy Policy, or customer service issues. 
  * Should you choose to subscribe, we will collect credit card information from you. We will use this information only for the purpose of processing payments made for the use of Less Annoying CRM, and will never share your billing information with any third party. 

You are never required to provide Less Annoying CRM with any personal information, but without the information detailed above, Less Annoying CRM will not be able to provide our service to you. 

Less Annoying CRM also collects usage data and statistics about its users' behavior and visitor information (browser, operating system, etc.) for the purposes of improving the product and service we provide, but this data is for internal use only is and is never shared with any third party. We do not honor Do Not Track requests. 

As a company, we are dedicated to keeping your personally identifiable information out of the hands of unauthorized viewers. We will always use the utmost discretion with your information, and we will never provide this information to any third party without your express consent, except in cases where: 

  * You were referred to our service by another user or a Less Annoying CRM affiliate, in which case your name will be shared with that referrer so that they can confirm that they received credit for the referral; no other personal information or contact information (e.g. your email address) will be shared with said referrer; 
  * Less Annoying CRM determines it necessary in order to preserve the safety of our users, employees, or the general public at large; or, 
  * The user's actions are deemed in violation of the service's Terms of Service. 

You have the right to access your personal information. You may change, update, correct, or remove your personal information from Less Annoying CRM at any time. To do so, contact us at help@lessannoyingcrm.com. 

Please be aware that Less Annoying CRM may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

**Your Data's Location and Ownership**

Less Annoying CRM uses third-party vendors/hosting partners to provide the hardware, networking, storage, and other technology needed to run the CRM. Less Annoying CRM, however, owns the code, databases, and the CRM application. However, you, the user, maintain ownership of any data that you enter into the CRM system. 

Each account has a single owner who will have control in the event of an ownership dispute amongst users within a single CRM account. The person who signs up for the service initially will be designated as the owner by default, but this user may request at any time that another user be given this status by contacting us at [help@lessannoyingcrm.com](mailto:help@lessannoyingcrm.com). 

Your identity is tied to the registered email address you have listed on your login settings page (this is also the email address we use to communicate with you). If you forget your password, or there is an ownership dispute, whoever has access to the registered email address for a user is considered to be the owner of that user's account. You must have access to your email account in order to be guaranteed access to the CRM. 

Anytime we make important changes to your account (e.g. changing ownership), we will verify your identity either by sending you a verification email, or by requiring you to log in and submit a contact form. In order to prevent unauthorized ownership changes, when ownership of an account is transferred between users, the original owner (i.e. the person who controls the email address associated with the original owner’s account) will have a two week window to protest and revert the change by responding to an email sent to them notifying them of the change. After this two week period, the ownership change is considered final and cannot be reverted. 

If a user changes the email address associated with their CRM account, a notification email will be sent to the previously listed email address. The owner of that email address will also have a two-week window during which they may revert the change by replying to that notice and informing Less Annoying CRM that the change was not authorized. If we do not receive an email requesting that we revert the change within two weeks of the change occurring, the change will be considered final and the owner of the original email address will have no claim to the account. 

If the owner of a multi-user account leaves the company, it may be necessary to make a different user the owner. If this situation arises, we will first contact the current owner for permission. If the current owner denies permission, then we will not switch ownership. If the owner doesn't reply, we will continue trying to contact them for 90 days. If the owner has not responded after 90 days and a different member of the CRM account can demonstrate to us that they should in fact be the rightful owner of the account, we will transfer ownership to them. If the new owner did not previously have access to all of the data in the CRM, we will not give them access to any data that they could not previously see. 

Because we store your information in multiple locations, including redundant back-ups, your information may remain on our servers after you delete your account. However, this information will never be accessed or used for any reason without your express consent. 

**EU-US & Swiss-US Privacy Shield Privacy Statement**

Less Annoying CRM complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Less Annoying CRM has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). 

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Less Annoying CRM commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Less Annoying CRM at [privacy@lessannoyingcrm.com](mailto:privacy@lessannoyingcrm.com). 

Less Annoying CRM has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint. Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel. 

Less Annoying CRM is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU or Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US or Swiss-US Privacy Shield, Less Annoying CRM is potentially liable. 

In compliance with EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield principle of Choice, you have the right to opt-in to allowing Less Annoying CRM to disclose your personal data to third parties. If you do not explicitly authorize Less Annoying CRM to do this, your data will not be disclosed. 

**Cookies**

Less Annoying CRM, like many online services, requires the use of cookies to operate. Cookies are small pieces of data from our system that is stored on your hard drive, and contain anonymous identifiers. We use these cookies to record session information, and they do not represent a threat to your personal information's security. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy at any time. In the event of any substantial changes to this Privacy Policy, users will be informed through the email address listed on their account or by the information being displayed prominently on the Less Annoying CRM website. 

**Questions/Comments**  
If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please do not hesitate to contact us at help@lessannoyingcrm.com. We will attempt to get back to you as soon as possible.
